<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Posts on So Woodoo</title><link>https://sowoodoo.github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on So Woodoo</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 16:50:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sowoodoo.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Why Christians Can Be Bad at Being Kind</title><link>https://sowoodoo.github.io/posts/85963971-why-christians-can-be-bad-at-being-kind/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 16:50:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sowoodoo.github.io/posts/85963971-why-christians-can-be-bad-at-being-kind/</guid><description>In a world rife with challenges and rancor, it is widely known that Christians are called to live counterculturally, marked by kindness in the face of hate or apathy. When we accept God’s invitation into relationship through faith, we often have an increased awareness of how His sacrificial love should impact our own lives (2 Corinthians 5:14-21). However, even believers can struggle to embody this foundational Christian virtue. Why might this be?</description></item><item><title>9 Lessons for New Christians ... And Old Ones</title><link>https://sowoodoo.github.io/posts/54875419-9-lessons-for-new-christians-and-old-ones/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 23:24:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sowoodoo.github.io/posts/54875419-9-lessons-for-new-christians-and-old-ones/</guid><description>Over the years, I've observed what is true for many people when they start their Christian journey. It can be very exciting and scary at the same time. You are filled with enthusiasm and eager to learn about God and what it means to follow Him. However, along with all the excitement and discovery, there will be some bumps in the road. Both new and seasoned believers face a long list of issues.</description></item><item><title>How Should Christians Approach Progress in Technology?</title><link>https://sowoodoo.github.io/posts/42458556-how-should-christians-approach-progress-in-technology/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 13:28:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sowoodoo.github.io/posts/42458556-how-should-christians-approach-progress-in-technology/</guid><description>Every culture, at every stage of its development has engaged with the process of technological innovation. In our day and age, many people view technological progress as inevitable, a natural consequence of human nature. The opinion is not unanimously shared but it seems to be particularly pervasive among tech enthusiasts and entrepreneurs who tend to support disruptive and transformative technological innovations. Conversely, a number of critics are alarmed at the pace of technological progress, fearing either that we lose control over the technology or even allowing for the possibility of supernatural involvement.</description></item><item><title>The Good and the Bad of Christian Fundamentalism</title><link>https://sowoodoo.github.io/posts/37492697-the-good-and-the-bad-of-christian-fundamentalism/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 02:47:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sowoodoo.github.io/posts/37492697-the-good-and-the-bad-of-christian-fundamentalism/</guid><description>Christian fundamentalism is an evangelical movement within Christianity that takes a literal stance on biblical teachings, especially relating to matters like the autority of the scripture, the deity of Jesus, and the inerrancy of the Bible. Although some might refer to it as narrow-minded or bigoted, many others believe it holds the last remnant of true Christianity. In this article, I will discuss both the good and the bad of Christian fundamentalism, acknowledging aspects that deserve appreciation and those that might generate controversy.</description></item><item><title>Why Do Christians Emphasize Hell Instead of Not Being with God in Heaven?</title><link>https://sowoodoo.github.io/posts/99026946-why-do-christians-emphasize-hell-instead-of-not-being-with-god-in-heaven/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 12:47:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sowoodoo.github.io/posts/99026946-why-do-christians-emphasize-hell-instead-of-not-being-with-god-in-heaven/</guid><description>When some non-Christians (or some former Christians) consider the teaching that presents a clear and compelling understanding of the concept of hell, they may wonder why Christian faith emphasizes the idea of "hell" rather than the less-terrifying notion of "not being with God" in heaven. Why not simply state that those who never believed or rejected Christ after believing just don't experience the presence of God in eternity? This is an intriguing question.</description></item><item><title>How to Actually Treat Other Believers Like Family</title><link>https://sowoodoo.github.io/posts/63024734-how-to-actually-treat-other-believers-like-family/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 05:11:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sowoodoo.github.io/posts/63024734-how-to-actually-treat-other-believers-like-family/</guid><description>All over the world, in various forms of Christianity, people often hear and repeat the sentiment that they should treat their fellow believers like family. However, as deeply rooted and well-intentioned as this idea is, most of us need practical tips and tools for making it a reality. The following six suggestions are provided with the goal of translating this admirable, biblical ideal from an empty cliché into concrete action.</description></item><item><title>What Does Jesus Teach Us about God's End-Times Plan?</title><link>https://sowoodoo.github.io/posts/15041599-what-does-jesus-teach-us-about-god-s-end-times-plan/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 13:31:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sowoodoo.github.io/posts/15041599-what-does-jesus-teach-us-about-god-s-end-times-plan/</guid><description>Christians sometimes struggle with end-times questions. But, we can turn to the greatest end-times Teacher -- Jesus Himself.
"Don't let anyone deceive you in any way, for that day [Jesus' return] will not come unless the rebellion comes first and the man of lawlessness is revealed, the son of destruction." 2 Thessalonians 2:3
The Bible's book of Matthew reveals an important question the disciples asked Jesus concerning the end times. It is here where Christians discover His teachings on end-times.</description></item><item><title>Why Pastors Struggle to Ask for Help (And How to Get Past It)</title><link>https://sowoodoo.github.io/posts/41152611-why-pastors-struggle-to-ask-for-help-and-how-to-get-past-it/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 09:10:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sowoodoo.github.io/posts/41152611-why-pastors-struggle-to-ask-for-help-and-how-to-get-past-it/</guid><description>Pastoral ministry is an incredibly rewarding, life-giving walk with God. But it can also be a challenging occupation filled with unique pressures and hurdles. One of the most common struggles pastors face, which often goes unspoken, is the challenge of asking and receiving help when necessary. Few of us naturally excel at admitting vulnerability or need. For pastors, this vulnerability may feel particularly acute given their role as spiritual leaders, and thus perceived need to always have the answers or appear fully confident.</description></item><item><title>Is it My Responsibility to Help the Widows and Orphans?</title><link>https://sowoodoo.github.io/posts/38042693-is-it-my-responsibility-to-help-the-widows-and-orphans/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sowoodoo.github.io/posts/38042693-is-it-my-responsibility-to-help-the-widows-and-orphans/</guid><description>Recently, I have seen a few people discussing the obligation we have as individuals to help the widows and orphans. This prompted me to write up some thoughts on this topic from a Biblical perspective.
The Passage Most Often Cited The most commonly referenced biblical text related to our responsibility to care for the vulnerable is found in the book of James, chapter 1, verse 27:
Religion that God our Father accepts as pure and faultless is this: to look after orphans and widows in their distress and to keep oneself from being polluted by the world.</description></item><item><title>Why Should Christians Evaluate What Their Lives Are Built On?</title><link>https://sowoodoo.github.io/posts/45698530-why-should-christians-evaluate-what-their-lives-are-built-on/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 09:16:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sowoodoo.github.io/posts/45698530-why-should-christians-evaluate-what-their-lives-are-built-on/</guid><description>"What shall it profit a man, if he shall gain the whole world, and lose his own soul?" - Jesus, Matthew 16:26. This question is one of many posed by Jesus that help us to take a step back and consider what we are most invested in. We can be consumed with accumulating wealth, pursuing social status or chasing after other transient things, when Jesus makes clear in this statement that we should prioritize our relationship with Him above all else.</description></item><item><title>4 Keys to Building Confidence in God When Life Falls Apart</title><link>https://sowoodoo.github.io/posts/42726641-4-keys-to-building-confidence-in-god-when-life-falls-apart/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 09:05:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sowoodoo.github.io/posts/42726641-4-keys-to-building-confidence-in-god-when-life-falls-apart/</guid><description>We've all been there: the unexpected blow, the heartache that rocked our faith to its core.
Jesus promised a life of abundant living, where troubles come in threes and faith makes leaping from the cliff feel safe. But what happens when our worst nightmare unfolds - the one that we just pray wouldn’t ever touch our families? What about the trials that shatter our notions of a good, powerful, loving God?</description></item><item><title>Guilt and the Great Deception in the Christian Life</title><link>https://sowoodoo.github.io/posts/47506479-guilt-and-the-great-deception-in-the-christian-life/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 20:45:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sowoodoo.github.io/posts/47506479-guilt-and-the-great-deception-in-the-christian-life/</guid><description>The dark secret of the Christian life is that often, we don’t feel like a Christian. There are times when we doubt our faith, and feel consumed by guilt—an all-encompassing sense of personal unworthiness. The truth is, our moments of doubt and guilt should not be surprising; what would be more shocking is if we never did. These emotions are not a sign we must now leave Christianity and embark on some spiritual wilderness journey.</description></item><item><title>Self-Care: Selfish Habit or Holy Endeavor?</title><link>https://sowoodoo.github.io/posts/74857791-self-care-selfish-habit-or-holy-endeavor/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 07:04:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sowoodoo.github.io/posts/74857791-self-care-selfish-habit-or-holy-endeavor/</guid><description>How many times have you heard self-care defined as a selfish act? As a child, were your attempts to address your own physical or emotional needs classified under the negative label of "selfishness"? While some argue that certain acts of self-focus can be narrowed down to a meager level of selfishness, the practice of genuine self-care is actually an essential expression of holiness and wholeness, both for ourselves and the world that we inhabit.</description></item><item><title>Why the Church Should Take Responsibility for Its Liberties and Freedoms</title><link>https://sowoodoo.github.io/posts/33289568-why-the-church-should-take-responsibility-for-its-liberties-and-freedoms/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 22:55:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sowoodoo.github.io/posts/33289568-why-the-church-should-take-responsibility-for-its-liberties-and-freedoms/</guid><description>In this essay, the relationship between the Christian faith community, the state and civil liberties is explored. The argument supports a notion that the Church should recognize its part in the protection of rights and freedoms due to its foundational influence on democratic institutions. To understand this position fully, it is necessary to grasp the historical context that gives rise to the contemporary western conception of liberty and freedom. The church’s influence on framing governments and laws as well as its role in advocating for social justice will be assessed.</description></item><item><title>Why People Are Losing Their Religion (and How the Church Can Respond)</title><link>https://sowoodoo.github.io/posts/73570018-why-people-are-losing-their-religion-and-how-the-church-can-respond/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 10:21:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sowoodoo.github.io/posts/73570018-why-people-are-losing-their-religion-and-how-the-church-can-respond/</guid><description>The decline of religious affiliation or belief has been a prevalent and significant phenomenon in Western societies. Books, articles, surveys, and conferences have swelled with a perceived need to analyze this shift, often referred to as secularization, spiritual-but-not-religious or non-religion. In the United States, polls show a downward trajectory in denominational adherence since 1990, as well as a rise in people self-identifying as religiously unaffiliated.^{[1]} Numbers are equally compelling from an international perspective: Declines in church attendance^{[2]}^{,[3]}, Christian practice and identification^{[4]}, and increases in non-religious perspectives are also seen in Western Europe^{[5]}^{,[6]}, Australia, Canada, and New Zealand.</description></item><item><title>Why Are There So Many Ideas about Heaven That Are Not Biblical?</title><link>https://sowoodoo.github.io/posts/65968725-why-are-there-so-many-ideas-about-heaven-that-are-not-biblical/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 18:20:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sowoodoo.github.io/posts/65968725-why-are-there-so-many-ideas-about-heaven-that-are-not-biblical/</guid><description>It's no secret that people hold a wide range of ideas and beliefs regarding heaven. The question is asked, "Why are there so many ideas about heaven that are not Biblical?" To address this question, it can be helpful to look at three contributing factors: Human nature, the diversity of Christian traditions, and the challenge of interpreting the Bible.
1. Human Nature First and foremost, human beings possess an innate desire to speculate about the unknown, including what happens after death.</description></item><item><title>One Key Reason Why Church Consultations Fail</title><link>https://sowoodoo.github.io/posts/83526765-one-key-reason-why-church-consultations-fail/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 17:55:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sowoodoo.github.io/posts/83526765-one-key-reason-why-church-consultations-fail/</guid><description>In the not-for-profit world, many ministries and churches do not operate efficiently. Some fail to be effective at reaching people for Jesus Christ. To address this challenge, I have consulted with a good number of Christian organisations. In these strategic processes, it has often been my experience that well-intentioned attempts to improve may still stumble unnecessarily. Some may even come to a complete halt. Here is one critical factor in why church consultations may fail, which, if understood and addressed appropriately, can greatly help these efforts succeed.</description></item></channel></rss>